This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
何っ
What?!
やめろ
カイ
バカ 何をする？
Stop it!
アキちゃん 追って
Kai!
You idiot! What are you doing?!
早く 瀬乃宮を止めろ
Aki, go!
君島レポートのとおりになるぞ
Quickly, stop Senomiya!
Or it'll turn out just as the Kimijima Reports said!
これは…
お姉ちゃん
That sound!
Sis!
中央口は 入り口専用となっております
The central gate is used for entrance only.
お姉ちゃん… お姉ちゃん
Sis... Sis!
残酷なる時は いつか
In the end, time unforgiving
契約の地さえ引き裂くの
たくさんが生み出す恐怖
Will draw the blood of covenant
真理のために今ここにいるよ
Everything scatters, leaving void
意外なCrazy
But we're here for the greater good
We Meet
目眩くこのシーン うかつな選択
Crazier than everyone, we need to dazzle
浮かび行く景色はやがて鮮やかに
The stage with our careless justice
And the scenery floating by becomes clearer
時間をすり抜ける
咆筺のメシア
As the Messiah of the Shoutbox slips through time
笑って 泣いて
僕らの一つの夢
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
願って 叫んで
どこまでも遠くへ
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
走って 飛ばして
気持ちの集まる場所
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
Run and break that place where feelings gather
愛しすぎるこの空の下で
Under this sky, oh so dear
明日を証明したくて
We're fighting for the future
---諸神字幕組---  本字幕由諸神字幕組出品,僅供學習交流之用 更多中日雙語字幕，請登錄 www.kamigami.org  台本：卷 　翻译:臭屁匠   苜汐瞳      校对: mam 　 后期:Ressul
Sis... But why?
お姉ちゃん… 何で…？
I should never have had a dream.
GunPro-2: boot up!
ガンつく２ 起動
I have control!
アイ ハブ コントロール
やめて… お姉ちゃん やめて
Stop it! Sis... stop it!
Don't!
駄目ぇぇぇぇぇ
No! Stop it! Stop it!
嫌だ やめて やめてー
Stop it!
やめてぇぇぇ
Aki!
アキちゃん
Aki! Are you hurt?
アキちゃん ケガは？
No way... a seizu—
まさか 発作 起こ…
She's...
いない…
She's gone...
お姉ちゃん 消えちゃった…
Aki...
アキ…
繰り返します 今日 午後２時５０分 史上最大規模の太陽嵐が 到達したもようです
I repeat, at approximately 2:50 PM today we
experienced the greatest solar flare ever recorded.
This will affect multiple areas, so prepare for interference...
この影響により 各所で電波障害などが…
Currently, the effects are global in scale.
現在 世界規模で この影響は出ており…
A large explosion of unknown origin
原因は分かりませんが
大規模な爆発があり万博アリーナが 完全に崩壊したもようです
caused the Expo Arena to completely collapse.
Aki, let's sit down there.
アキちゃん そこ座ろう
What the hell is that?
何だ あれ…
The Grand Obelisk...
グランドオベリスク…
[注：Obelisk：方尖塔 為古代埃及及西亞常見的一種紀念碑 亦可作為日晷使用]
『ガンヴァレル』の最終回に出てくる軌道エレベーター
The orbital elevator from the final episode of Gunvarrel...
No way! There's no way something like that could exist...
そんな… そんなもの 存在するはずが…
Ah, finally I found you, Kaito, Akiho!
海翔君 あき穂ちゃん ここにおったか
Sorry, could you look after Aki for a while?
すいません アキちゃんのこと 見ててもらえませんか
Aki, I'll be back soon.
アキちゃん すぐ戻るから
Currently, both Haneda and Narita airports are blocked off.
現在 羽田 成田 両空港は封鎖されており
空の交通機関は まひした状態が続いています
Transportation is at a standstill.
Yes.
はい
Come in.
どうぞ
Kagome, Kagome, the caged bird
『かごめ かごめ』
『かごのなかの とりは』
『いついつ でやる』
When, oh when, will it come out?
『よあけの ばんに』
On the eve of dawn
『つるとかめが すべった』
The crane and the turtle slipped
What is this?
どういうことだ
Someone created a fake image?
誰かが 偽の画像を流してる？
According to Iru-O, there were explosions all over the place.
「居ル夫」の情報だと爆発で あちこち 破壊されてるってあるけど…
The name of that magic... is NoAH's Ark.
魔法の正体
ノアの箱舟だ
電磁波照射装置肉眼に ＡＲのような幻影を見せる装置だよ
It's an electromagnetic irradiation device.
Apparatus to create illusions just like AR.
Are you injured?
ケガしてるのか
The SS Anenome mass fainting was a human body experiment.
あねもね号 集団失神事件はこのための人体実験だったんだよ
What do you mean?
どういうことだよ
What do you think caused global confusion these past few hours?
この数時間の 世界の混乱は何が原因で 引き起こされたと思う
It was a solar flare.
太陽嵐でしょ
There was no solar flare.
太陽嵐など来てはいない
"The solar flare is causing a power problem in every major city,
太陽嵐によってあらゆる都市で停電が起き 交通は まひし
traffic is paralyzed, and Odaiba is in ruins."
お台場は崩壊している
Just where did you read that information?
その情報は どこから もたらされている？何を通じて知った？
Through what means did you learn it?
Explosion of unknown origin at the Expo Arena
Huge explosion at the Expo in Tokyo
Propaganda.
プロパガンダ
Everyone's in panic because of a mere illusion. That's what's happening.
それに踊らされ ありもしない幻にパニックになっているのが
今の状況だ
No way...
そんな… 何のために
But why?!
Project Atom.
プロジェクト アトゥム
The ultimate goal of this mission is to generate an artificial substorm
作戦の最終目標はＳＥＲＮから獲得した ブラックホール爆弾を
[注：SERN：架空機構 映射現實中的CERN 即歐洲核子研究組織]
in Earth's magnetosphere by launching black hole bombs acquired from SERN
ＶＡＢで組み立て済みのロケットに装着し 宇宙空間に発射
[注：VAB：Vehicle Assembly Building 航太飛行器裝配大樓]
into space with rockets assembled at the VAB and detonating them.
We must swiftly take control of targets Alpha and Beta.
爆発させ 人為的に 地球磁気圏に サブストームを引き起こすことにある
[注：亞爆：亦稱磁層亞爆或極光亞爆 是發生於地球磁層中的輕微擾動現象]
We must launch the rockets before this chaos we created calms down
そのためには ポイント α βを 速やかに制圧し
現状 意図的に引き起こした 混乱が収束し
政府 警察機関が 動きだす前に
and government and law enforcement units make their move.
ロケットを 発射しなければならない
The substorm should affect around 5 billion people.
サブストームが起きれば 影響は ５０億の人類に及ぶ
Just as Kimijima said it would.
君島が言っていたようにな
So you were the mastermind behind this.
その首謀者が あんたってわけか
You really believe that...
やはり そう思っていたか
Exactly as he wanted it.
まさに やつの思うつぼだな
I oppose the ways of the Committee of 300.
私は 三百人委員会のやり方に 異を唱える者だ
So you're not one of them?
連中の一味じゃないのか
I discovered that the Committee of 300 is helping the mastermind of Project Atom
私は 三百人委員会が プロジェクト·アトゥムを発案したある者に手を貸しているという 情報をつかみ
and tried to follow their trail with Senomiya Misaki.
瀬乃宮みさ希と共に その者を追い続けていたのだ
With Misa?!
ミサ姉？
Eventually, I noticed something weird.
そのうちに 奇妙なことに気付いた
I'll look up this Kimijima Kou, whoever he is.
[大德淳和：關於那個叫君島豪的人 我也去查查看吧]
Something weird?
奇妙なこと？
Iru-O. The SS Anemone incident.
「居ル夫」 あねもね号事件 謎のレポート ＥＧＩシステム
Mysterious reports. The EGI system.
Yukifune Airi. Senomiya Misaki.
行舟 愛理 瀬乃宮みさ希
There's only one person connected to all of these.
これら全てと関わりを持つ人物は １人しか いないということに
Don't tell me...
まさか…
Oh yes.
そうだ
He "leaked" information in the form of reports and made it look like someone else is the culprit.
レポートという形で 自ら情報を流し
あたかも 犯人は別にいるように 見せ掛け
He skillfully hid the fact that he's the main villain.
首謀者であることを 巧妙に隠していた男
Arrived at point Beta. Commencing the suppression operation now.
ポイントβに到達 これより 制圧行動に入る
Roger.
了解 ポイントαは制圧完了
We are in control of point Alpha.
I hate the rain.
雨は嫌い
Senomiya Misaki is probably a puppet of Kimijima Kou.
おそらく 瀬乃宮みさ希は君島コウの駒だ
No way! Misa!
ミサ姉が…
She created an illusion of Senomiya Misaki,
幻の瀬乃宮みさ希を つくり上げぎりぎりまで 私たちの目を ごまかし
deceived us until the last possible moment,
and meanwhile, headed for the rocket launch base
自らは もう１体のＳＵＭＥＲＡＧＩと共に種子島の ロケット発射場に向かう
at Tanegashima with the other SUMERAGI.
No way... No way!
そんな… そんなこと…
Aki! Aki!
アキちゃん アキちゃん
Ah, Kaito!
海翔君
Where's Aki?
アキちゃんは？
She vanished when I took my eyes off her for a moment...
それが ちょっと 目を離した隙に いなくなってしまって
Aki!
アキちゃん
Let's go back to Tanegashima.
種子島に戻ろう
We've gotta see Misa again.
もう一度 ミサ姉に会うんだ
There's so much we need to ask her about.
ちゃんと 確かめなきゃ いけないことが たくさんある
It doesn't matter. Not anymore.
いいよ… もう いいよ
I don't wanna see her or talk with her.
会いたくもないし 話したくもない
What's that? This is the time you should bring out your crazy optimi—
どうしたんだよ？ こんなときこそ無駄に前向きなアキちゃん…
I'm not optimistic at all!
うちは 全然 ちっとも 前向きなんかじゃない
I always feel like crying,
泣きたいときは しょっちゅうあるし
お姉ちゃんに 嫌われてるんじゃないかって ずっと びくびくして
and I've been scared that she hates me all this time.
I couldn't even see her... It was so scary.
会いにも行けないし 怖かった…
Yeah, I've been scared all this time.
そうだよ ずっと怖かった
Ever since she called my plain and ordinary.
「平凡止まりだ」って言われた あのときから
絶対 追い付けないんじゃないかって
I was afraid I could never catch up to her.
That she would never acknowledge me at all.
お姉ちゃんに 認めてもらうことなんて 一生 ないんじゃないかって
ロボットなんて 造らなければよかった
I should never have built this stupid robot.
I should never have tried to catch up to her.
お姉ちゃんに追い付こうなんて 思わなければよかった
夢なんて 持たなければよかった
I should never have had a dream.
It's just as she said.
お姉ちゃんの言うとおりだ
ガンつく２ ただの がらくただったんだね
The GunPro-2 was just a pile of junk.
I see.
そっか…
You let me down.
ちょっと がっかりしたよ
It's just as she said.
お姉ちゃんの言うとおりだ
The GunPro-2 was just a pile of junk.
ガンつく２ ただの がらくただったんだね
Aki!
アキちゃん
I'm going to meet Misa after all.
俺 やっぱり ミサ姉に会いに行く もう一度
Once more.
Why?
どうして？
気に入らない
I don't like this.
I can't just weep in the corner about this defeat.
やられたまま 泣き寝入りなんて できない
I was tricked and lured into a fight without even noticing.
こっちを だまして 知らないうちに勝負に持ち込まれてたんだ
I can't just lose like this.
負けっ放しで終われないよ
Both of us have been chasing after her all this time.
俺もアキちゃんもさ ずっと ず～っと ミサ姉の背中を 追い掛けてきたよね
Just when we thought she was helping us, she's suddenly further away than ever...
泣きながら助けてくれたと 思ったら 訳が分からないくらい 突き放したり…
Aren't you fed up yet?
いいかげん 頭に こないか
I don't know...
分かんないよ…
Well, I am!
俺は きてる
At least, I don't wanna lose to her!
俺は もう ミサ姉に負けたくない
いや 違う
No! I don't want you to lose to her!
アキちゃんに ミサ姉に負けてほしくない
カイ…
Kai...
You came proudly to the Expo to show Misa the GunPro-2, didn't you?!
胸張って 万博に来て ミサ姉に ガンつく２を見せに来たんだろ？
Then don't just let it all be for nothing!
だったら これまでのもの 全部 無駄にするなよ
あの いつも上から目線のミサ姉の首根っこ つかんで
Grab her disdainful head in a headlock and tell her,
「どうだ すごいだろ？」って
"It's awesome, isn't it?! That's not ordinary, is it now?!"
「全然 平凡じゃないだろ？」って 言ってやろうよ
「参りました」って言わせようよ
Make her admit that she lost!
You're not being your usual self...
何か いつものカイじゃないみたい
「なーに そんなに熱くなってんの？」って いつものカイに言われちゃうよ
You'd tell yourself "What are you getting all worked up about?"
いや…
Thanks...
ありがと
さっきの撤回するよ
I take back what I said.
ガンつく２は がらくたじゃない
The GunPro-2 isn't junk.
Get my uncle! We're going back to the island.
叔父貴を呼んでこい 島に戻るぜ
Mitchie...
ミッチー
But Haneda and Narita are closed...
でも 空港は 羽田も成田も…
Those aren't the only airports in Tokyo.
東京の空港は それだけじゃないぜ
Haven't you heard of the Choufu airport?
調布空港って知ってるか？
調布？
Choufu?
And there's a certain facility right next to it.
ちなみに その空港に隣接している施設な
This is a useful piece of exclusive knowledge, so remember it!
こいつが豆知識だ
特別に教えてやるから 覚えとけ
ＪＡＸＡ 調布航空宇宙センターってんだ
It's the JAXA Choufu Aerospace Center!
Real estate, rent
Commit Inc.
Catering, consult
ｋｔｋｒ 完全に一致
[注：「ktkr」:網路用語 「キタコレ」縮略語 表達激動開心之情]
That's it! Perfect match!
The company that paid Kimijima Kou's rent is the same as the one Maguyan dealt with
君島コウの別荘の 電気代を払っていた会社は
マグヤンの取引先の会社
そして ママが『ガンヴァレル』を 作っていたときのスタジオの融資会社
and also the one that financed the studio where Mama worked on Gunvarrel.
Mama must've been threated just like Maguyan.
やっぱり ママは マグヤンと同じように 無理やり作らされてて
But she broke out and tried to tell the truth.
何とか逃げ出して その真実を伝えようとした…
ママ…
Mom...
Frau, you've got a visitor!
フラウ 誰か 客が来たみたいだぜ
It's not nice to just ignore them!
対応しないと よくないですよ
誰も いない
No one's there...
Don't move.
動くな
This is Priest One.
こちら プリースト１ ターゲットＢを確保
Target B secured.
I repeat. Target B secured.
繰り返す ターゲットＢを確保
What's wrong?
どうした？
空港制圧に向かった２人が反応しない
The two who are supposed to take control of the airport won't respond.
You can call them all you want. They won't reply.
呼んでも出ませんよ
I put them to sleep.
一眠りしてもらったので
もう大丈夫です
It's okay now.
Mitchie, learn to drive...
ミッチー 運転 荒過ぎ
気持ち悪い
I feel sick...
You've got no time to whine!
弱音 吐いてる場合じゃないぞ
It might get even rougher now.
今度は もっと 揺れるかもしれないんだからな
あれは…？
What?
Ms. Tennouji told me that there's a chance of a terrorist attack.
天王寺さんに言われていたんだ近々 テロが起きる可能性がある
She told me to come to the Choufu airport if something happened.
もし 何かあったら 調布空港に行くようにって
Ms. Tennouji did?
天王寺さんが…
Take that. It will come handy.
それを持っていけ 何かの役に立つだろう
That, and I've got some friends in Tanegashima.
それと 種子島には 私の仲間がいる
You probably don't know her, but if you see S Braun, tell her I say hi.
会ったことはないが…
[注：S.Braun：名字源於「Steins；Gate」中其父Mr.Braun天王寺裕吾]
エスブラウンに会ったら よろしく伝えてくれ
Wait, could that S Braun...
もしかして エスブラウンって…
We've got no time! Hurry!
さぁ 時間がないぞ 早く
Kagome, Kagome, the caged bird
「かごめ かごめ」
「かごのなかの とりは」
「いついつ でやる」
When, oh when, will it come out?
This voice... Airi?
この声… 愛理？
On the eve of dawn
「よあけの ばんに」
「つるとかめが すべった」
The crane and the turtle slipped
「うしろのしょうめん だーれ」
Who is it in front of behind?
Airi?
愛理…
The ghost from the Space Hill park?
宇宙ヶ丘公園に出るっていう 幽霊か？
That was made based on the real girl's data...
あれは 実在する女の子のデータを基に つくったんだ
君島コウが
by Kimijima Kou.
Then she's...
じゃあ あの子が？
I won't let you take off from here.
君たちを ここから飛び立たせはしない
You can only leave over my dead body.
どうしても行きたければ ひいていくといい
Are you Airi?
愛理… なのか？
I'm a body.
私は生身だ
If you pass over my dead body, you'll cut my flesh, break my bones, crush my organs, draw my blood.
ひけば 肉は裂け 骨は砕け
内臓はつぶれ 血は流れ出す
その覚悟があるのなら…
Are you ready for that?
Who're you?!
あんたは誰だ
まあいい 君には 色々 協力してもらったからね
Oh well. You helped me quite a lot, so I'll show you this once.
一度くらいは見せてあげるよ
You should know the way by now.
方法は分かるだろ？ 君なら
ＡＩ？
An AI?
No. Convert one's consciousness and memories to data and store it on the network.
違うね
人格や記憶をデータ化して ネットワーク上に移植する
Haven't you heard about that?
聞いたことあるだろ
まさか…
Don't tell me...
I found out quite a bit while
experimenting on Yukifune Airi.
行舟 愛理を実験台に 色々 模索してね
不完全ではあるのだが 成功したんだよ
It might be imperfect, but it's still a success.
君島コウ…
Kimijima Kou...
I'm someone who has gained eternal life on the network.
僕は ネットワーク上に存在する永遠の命を持った
一つの人格さ
それはふとした瞬間に
All those unexpected moments
As you mumble on and on
君がつぶやくいくつもの言葉
Will overcome even my standards
それがいつしか価値観さえも
超えてしまうんだよ
In the end
All those goodbyes we said
いくつもの別れを告げ 僕らは
As we climb the stairway to the future
明日への階段をのぼる
とめどなく零れ落ちる雫も
Just as raindrops fall no matter what we do
光が照らすなら この星は繋がっている
Light will always hold this planet together
奇跡のように命が集まって
Lives gather as if by some miracle
にぎやかな景色は輪郭になる
Showing the outline of a lively scene
泣きたい眩しいエピローグ
An epilogue so bright it brings tears to our eyes
取り上げる思いが
The sky painted by the hearts of those looking up
描いた空
柔らかな風が吹き
The wind blows gently stroking
Turning into a new path
新しい道となり
A path that will always
いつだってその道は
Lead us to this place
この場所に繋がってる
Gunvarrel Ankh Striker!!
Tune in next week too!
Too!